<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.7.3">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2018-07-16T15:35:42+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/</id><title type="html">West Sussex JSNA Website</title><subtitle>The Public Health and Social Research Unit is responsible for the evidence base to underpin strategic decision-making in West Sussex County Council and its partners.</subtitle><author><name>PHSRU</name></author><entry><title type="html">West Sussex Oral Health Needs Assessment 2018</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/needs-assessment/oral-health-needs-assessment-2018/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="West Sussex Oral Health Needs Assessment 2018" /><published>2018-05-30T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2018-05-30T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/needs-assessment/oral-health-needs-assessment-2018</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/needs-assessment/oral-health-needs-assessment-2018/">&lt;p&gt;West Sussex County Council has now published the Oral Health Needs Assessment for Children and Young People. The needs assessment provides an overview of the current standard of oral health in children within West Sussex, and the provision of oral health services. It also summarises the risk factors and wider determinants associated with poor oral health. It makes recommendations which will be used to inform a strategic approach to oral health improvement in the county.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Oral Health Needs Assessment has been developed by the West Sussex Public Health Directorate with the support of Public Health England. Consultation was sought from the Local Dental Network, dental professionals and those who work in children’s services.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/assets/starting-well/West Sussex OHNA in Children and Young People 2018 Executive Summary.pdf&quot;&gt;West Sussex Oral Health Needs Assessment in Children and Young People 2018 Executive Summary (PDF, 714KB)&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/assets/starting-well/West Sussex OHNA in Children and Young People 2018.pdf&quot;&gt;West Sussex Oral Health Needs Assessment in Children and Young People 2018 (PDF, 2.14MB)&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>PHSRU</name></author><category term="needs-assessment" /><summary type="html">The West Sussex Oral Health Needs Assessment for Children and Young People is now complete.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">West Sussex Oral Health Needs Assessment 2018</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/needs-assessment/oral-health-needs-assessment-2018/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="West Sussex Oral Health Needs Assessment 2018" /><published>2018-05-30T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2018-05-30T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/needs-assessment/oral-health-needs-assessment-2018</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/needs-assessment/oral-health-needs-assessment-2018/">&lt;p&gt;How would you like to contribute to improving the oral health of children in West Sussex?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;West Sussex County Council has drafted the 2018 West Sussex Oral Health Needs Assessment and is looking to obtain feedback and comments. The current draft has been developed by the West Sussex Public Health Directorate with the support of Public Health England and Jackie Sowerbutts, Dental Public Health Consultant.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We would value your input to help shape the document and contribute to the recommendations which will be used to inform an Oral Health Improvement Strategy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please direct any comments or feedback to &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:Louis.Hall@westsussex.gov.uk&quot;&gt;Louis.Hall@westsussex.gov.uk&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We look forward to hearing from you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://jsna.westsussex.gov.uk/wp-content/uploads/2018/05/West-Sussex-OHNA-2018-Final-Draft.docx&quot;&gt;Final Draft of West Sussex Oral Health Needs Assessment 2018&lt;/a&gt; (Word Document, 13.2MB).&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>PHSRU</name></author><category term="needs-assessment" /><summary type="html">We'd appreciate comments on this draft of the West Sussex Oral Health Needs Assessment.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">West Sussex Pharmaceutical Needs Assessment (PNA) 2018</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/needs-assessment/west-sussex-pharmaceutical-needs-assessment-pna-2018/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="West Sussex Pharmaceutical Needs Assessment (PNA) 2018" /><published>2018-03-05T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2018-03-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/needs-assessment/west-sussex-pharmaceutical-needs-assessment-pna-2018/</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/needs-assessment/west-sussex-pharmaceutical-needs-assessment-pna-2018/">&lt;p&gt;West Sussex’s Health and Wellbeing Board has now published its findings and recommendations on pharmaceutical service provision across the County. The Pharmaceutical Needs Assessment (PNA) looks at the provision and availability of pharmaceutical services provided by pharmacies, dispensing doctors and appliance contractors. It is used by NHS England, Clinical Commissioning Groups and Local Authorities in making decisions about pharmaceutical services. It also contains information about West Sussex such as population growth, age profiles, deprivation and local health and wellbeing priorities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;West Sussex residents and pharmaceutical service providers were consulted for their views during the development of the PNA and feedback is included in the &lt;a href=&quot;http://jsna.westsussex.gov.uk/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/West-Sussex-PNA-2018-Full-Report.pdf&quot;&gt;PNA report (2018)&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://jsna.westsussex.gov.uk/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/West-Sussex-PNA-2018-Appendices.pdf&quot;&gt;appendices&lt;/a&gt;. The PNA concluded that current services are adequate to meet pharmaceutical needs. However, it recommended that there is scope for improving patient access and choice for certain services and geographic areas. Further details about the PNA and previous reports can be found &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.westsussex.gov.uk/pna&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>PHSRU</name></author><category term="needs-assessment" /><summary type="html">West Sussex’s Health and Wellbeing Board has now published its findings and recommendations on pharmaceutical service provision across the County. The Pharmaceutical Needs Assessment (PNA) looks at the provision and availability of pharmaceutical services provided by pharmacies, dispensing doctors and appliance contractors. It is used by NHS England, Clinical Commissioning Groups and Local Authorities in making decisions about pharmaceutical services. It also contains information about West Sussex such as population growth, age profiles, deprivation and local health and wellbeing priorities.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">West Sussex Children Looked After Needs Assessment 2017</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/needs-assessment/west-sussex-children-looked-needs-assessment-2017/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="West Sussex Children Looked After Needs Assessment 2017" /><published>2017-12-12T12:44:30+00:00</published><updated>2017-12-12T12:44:30+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/needs-assessment/west-sussex-children-looked-needs-assessment-2017</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/needs-assessment/west-sussex-children-looked-needs-assessment-2017/">In late 2015 OFSTED conducted an inspection of services for children in need of help and protection, children looked after and care leavers, and a review of the effectiveness of the Local Safeguarding Children Board.  Services for children provided and delivered by the council, including those in need of help and protection and those looked after, were judged to require improvement.  This led to the development of the West Sussex OFSTED Improvement Plan 2016 – 2017, in which the imperative to produce a needs assessment for looked after children was identified.  National and local datasets were analysed and the views of service leaders sought.  The needs assessment reports on topics such as demographics, legal status, placement characteristics, engagement and voice, health, education and care leavers.

[West Sussex Children Looked After Needs Assessment 2017 (PDF)](http://jsna.westsussex.gov.uk/wp-content/uploads/2017/12/West-Sussex-Children-Looked-After-Needs-Assessment-2017.pdf)</content><author><name>PHSRU</name></author><category term="needs-assessment" /><summary type="html">In late 2015 OFSTED conducted an inspection of services for children in need of help and protection, children looked after and care leavers, and a review of the effectiveness of the Local Safeguarding Children Board. Services for children provided and delivered by the council, including those in need of help and protection and those looked after, were judged to require improvement. This led to the development of the West Sussex OFSTED Improvement Plan 2016 – 2017, in which the imperative to produce a needs assessment for looked after children was identified. National and local datasets were analysed and the views of service leaders sought. The needs assessment reports on topics such as demographics, legal status, placement characteristics, engagement and voice, health, education and care leavers.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">West Sussex Pharmaceutical Needs Assessment (PNA)</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/needs-assessment/2017/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="West Sussex Pharmaceutical Needs Assessment (PNA)" /><published>2017-09-01T11:00:15+01:00</published><updated>2017-09-01T11:00:15+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/needs-assessment/2017</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/needs-assessment/2017/">&lt;h2&gt;What is a PNA?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since 1 April 2013, every Health and Wellbeing Board (HWB) in England has had a statutory responsibility to publish and keep up to date a statement of the need for pharmaceutical services of the population within its area. This is referred to as a Pharmaceutical Needs Assessment (PNA). The PNA:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;looks at the current provision of pharmaceutical services across the West Sussex HWB area;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;assesses whether service provision meets the current and future needs of the population and;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;identifies any potential gaps to service delivery.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The PNA is a key document which is used by:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;NHS England to inform decisions about applications for new, or changes to existing pharmaceutical services, and the commissioning of NHS-funded services that can be provided by local community pharmacies.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Local authorities and Clinical Commissioning Groups (CCG) when commissioning services to meet local health needs and priorities.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Consultation: Have Your Say about the West Sussex draft PNA&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The West Sussex draft PNA has been published and you are invited to read and give your feedback or comments on it. The draft can be found in the supporting documents below. Feedback provided will be considered for the final PNA, prior to its publication in February 2018. All responses are confidential and no personal identifiable information will be used in the report.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The draft PNA consultation will be available from &lt;strong&gt;Friday 1 September 2017 until Sunday 5 November 2017.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The best way to comment is by completing the online consultation survey. You can access it with this link:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://haveyoursay.westsussex.gov.uk/public-health/pna&quot;&gt;https://haveyoursay.westsussex.gov.uk/public-health/pna&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you have any queries or wish to request a free of charge paper copy of the draft PNA, please contact:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Aloisia Katsande
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;mailto:ACDJSNA@westsussex.gov.uk?subject=West Sussex Pharmaceutical Needs Assessment (SEPT17)&quot;&gt;Email&lt;/a&gt;, Telephone: 0330 222 5602&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ryan Walkley
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;mailto:ACDJSNA@westsussex.gov.uk?subject=West Sussex Pharmaceutical Needs Assessment (SEPT17)&quot;&gt;Email&lt;/a&gt;, Telephone: 0330 222 7586&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you wish to access the previous PNA and supplementary statements, these can be found &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.westsussex.gov.uk/pna&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Supporting documents&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://jsna.westsussex.gov.uk/wp-content/uploads/2017/09/West-Sussex-Draft-PNA-2018-full-report-consultation.pdf&quot;&gt;West Sussex Draft PNA 2018 full report - consultation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://jsna.westsussex.gov.uk/wp-content/uploads/2017/09/West-Sussex-Draft-PNA-2018-appendices-consulation.pdf&quot;&gt;West Sussex Draft PNA 2018 appendices - consulation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(Please note that these links will only be active during the consultation period.)&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>PHSRU</name></author><category term="needs-assessment" /><summary type="html">What is a PNA? Since 1 April 2013, every Health and Wellbeing Board (HWB) in England has had a statutory responsibility to publish and keep up to date a statement of the need for pharmaceutical services of the population within its area. This is referred to as a Pharmaceutical Needs Assessment (PNA). The PNA: looks at the current provision of pharmaceutical services across the West Sussex HWB area; assesses whether service provision meets the current and future needs of the population and; identifies any potential gaps to service delivery. The PNA is a key document which is used by: NHS England to inform decisions about applications for new, or changes to existing pharmaceutical services, and the commissioning of NHS-funded services that can be provided by local community pharmacies. Local authorities and Clinical Commissioning Groups (CCG) when commissioning services to meet local health needs and priorities. Consultation: Have Your Say about the West Sussex draft PNA The West Sussex draft PNA has been published and you are invited to read and give your feedback or comments on it. The draft can be found in the supporting documents below. Feedback provided will be considered for the final PNA, prior to its publication in February 2018. All responses are confidential and no personal identifiable information will be used in the report. The draft PNA consultation will be available from Friday 1 September 2017 until Sunday 5 November 2017. The best way to comment is by completing the online consultation survey. You can access it with this link: https://haveyoursay.westsussex.gov.uk/public-health/pna If you have any queries or wish to request a free of charge paper copy of the draft PNA, please contact: Aloisia Katsande Email, Telephone: 0330 222 5602 Ryan Walkley Email, Telephone: 0330 222 7586 If you wish to access the previous PNA and supplementary statements, these can be found here. Supporting documents West Sussex Draft PNA 2018 full report - consultation West Sussex Draft PNA 2018 appendices - consulation (Please note that these links will only be active during the consultation period.)</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Suicide Prevention - draft strategy now available</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/update/suicide-prevention-draft-strategy-now-available/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Suicide Prevention - draft strategy now available" /><published>2017-07-31T08:16:16+01:00</published><updated>2017-07-31T08:16:16+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/update/suicide-prevention-draft-strategy-now-available</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/update/suicide-prevention-draft-strategy-now-available/">&lt;h2&gt;Suicide is the biggest killer of men aged 49 and under and the leading cause of death in people aged 20–34 years in the UK.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is widely recognised that suicides are preventable. A local level &lt;a href=&quot;http://jsna.westsussex.gov.uk/reports/subject-specific-needs-assessments/suicide-prevention/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Suicide Prevention Strategy&lt;/a&gt; has been developed to present a set of priority areas for action in West Sussex for 2017 to 2020 that are aligned with national strategic priorities. These are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Focus on reducing suicides in vulnerable middle aged and older people, particularly those experiencing financial difficulties and social isolation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Focus on preventing suicides in people in contact with mental health services, particularly those recently discharged or disengaged from care &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Focus on preventing suicide in people who misuse alcohol or drugs, particularly those with a dual diagnosis &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Focus on reducing self-harm, particularly in young people &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Focus on preventing suicide in people with long term conditions or requiring end of life care, and their carers &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Improve support for people bereaved or affected by suicide &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Increase confidence and skills of paid and volunteer workers to support people at risk of suicide, maximising the use of existing resources and support &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Reduce access to the means of suicide, focusing on self-poisoning, railways and other public places &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Monitor suicide patterns and trends in West Sussex &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This strategy was based on evidence drawn from the &lt;a href=&quot;http://jsna.westsussex.gov.uk/wp-content/uploads/2017/07/West-Sussex-Suicide-Audit-2017.pdf&quot;&gt;West Sussex Suicide Audit (2017)&lt;/a&gt;, engagement with front-line workers via an &lt;a href=&quot;http://jsna.westsussex.gov.uk/wp-content/uploads/2017/07/Suicide-prevention-consultation-Final-25.07.17.pdf&quot;&gt;online consultation&lt;/a&gt; , a brief &lt;a href=&quot;http://jsna.westsussex.gov.uk/wp-content/uploads/2017/07/Brief-review-of-effective-models-of-suicide-prevention.pdf&quot;&gt;review of effective models of suicide prevention&lt;/a&gt; and local level analysis of &lt;a href=&quot;http://jsna.westsussex.gov.uk/wp-content/uploads/2017/07/Briefing-Self-Harm-May-2017.pdf&quot;&gt;emergency hospital admissions for self-harm&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The multi-agency West Sussex Suicide Prevention Steering Group was set up to coordinate local implementation of the national strategy ‘Preventing Suicides in England’. This group will oversee and support development and delivery of the local strategic action plan which addresses each of the above priorities. The strategy will be formerly signed off by the Health and Wellbeing Board in November 2017 and action plan will be available in 2018. &lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>PHSRU</name></author><category term="update" /><summary type="html">Suicide is the biggest killer of men aged 49 and under and the leading cause of death in people aged 20–34 years in the UK. It is widely recognised that suicides are preventable. A local level Suicide Prevention Strategy has been developed to present a set of priority areas for action in West Sussex for 2017 to 2020 that are aligned with national strategic priorities. These are: Focus on reducing suicides in vulnerable middle aged and older people, particularly those experiencing financial difficulties and social isolation Focus on preventing suicides in people in contact with mental health services, particularly those recently discharged or disengaged from care Focus on preventing suicide in people who misuse alcohol or drugs, particularly those with a dual diagnosis Focus on reducing self-harm, particularly in young people Focus on preventing suicide in people with long term conditions or requiring end of life care, and their carers Improve support for people bereaved or affected by suicide Increase confidence and skills of paid and volunteer workers to support people at risk of suicide, maximising the use of existing resources and support Reduce access to the means of suicide, focusing on self-poisoning, railways and other public places Monitor suicide patterns and trends in West Sussex This strategy was based on evidence drawn from the West Sussex Suicide Audit (2017), engagement with front-line workers via an online consultation , a brief review of effective models of suicide prevention and local level analysis of emergency hospital admissions for self-harm. The multi-agency West Sussex Suicide Prevention Steering Group was set up to coordinate local implementation of the national strategy ‘Preventing Suicides in England’. This group will oversee and support development and delivery of the local strategic action plan which addresses each of the above priorities. The strategy will be formerly signed off by the Health and Wellbeing Board in November 2017 and action plan will be available in 2018.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Have Your Say in the Pharmaceutical Needs Assessment (PNA) survey</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/needs-assessment/survey/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Have Your Say in the Pharmaceutical Needs Assessment (PNA) survey" /><published>2017-02-25T14:00:31+00:00</published><updated>2017-02-25T14:00:31+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/needs-assessment/survey</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/needs-assessment/survey/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;alignnone size-full wp-image-4661&quot; src=&quot;/assets/PNA-image-shutterstock_73916767.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; width=&quot;1000&quot; height=&quot;687&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thank you for taking the time to visit the West Sussex Pharmaceutical Needs Assessment (PNA) survey page. The PNA looks at the current and future pharmaceutical service needs of the people in West Sussex and identifies any potential gaps to service delivery.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;West Sussex County Council was conducting surveys to better understand local views on pharmaceutical services across West Sussex. The patient/public survey is now closed. Thank you for taking part. The findings from the survey will be used to inform the PNA. There will also be an opportunity to comment on the draft PNA during the consultation period in the near future, so please keep an eye out for it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To find out more about the PNA, please visit &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.westsussex.gov.uk/pna&quot;&gt;www.westsussex.gov.uk/pna&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>PHSRU</name></author><category term="needs-assessment" /><summary type="html">Thank you for taking the time to visit the West Sussex Pharmaceutical Needs Assessment (PNA) survey page. The PNA looks at the current and future pharmaceutical service needs of the people in West Sussex and identifies any potential gaps to service delivery. West Sussex County Council was conducting surveys to better understand local views on pharmaceutical services across West Sussex. The patient/public survey is now closed. Thank you for taking part. The findings from the survey will be used to inform the PNA. There will also be an opportunity to comment on the draft PNA during the consultation period in the near future, so please keep an eye out for it. &amp;nbsp; To find out more about the PNA, please visit www.westsussex.gov.uk/pna</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">West Sussex Children’s Workforce Public Health Data Profile (2016)</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/health-profile/west-sussex-childrens-workforce-public-health-data-profile-2016-now-available-download/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="West Sussex Children's Workforce Public Health Data Profile (2016)" /><published>2017-01-04T15:45:52+00:00</published><updated>2017-01-04T15:45:52+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/health-profile/west-sussex-childrens-workforce-public-health-data-profile-2016-now-available-download</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/health-profile/west-sussex-childrens-workforce-public-health-data-profile-2016-now-available-download/">&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;http://jsna.westsussex.gov.uk/wp-content/uploads/2017/01/West-Sussex-Childrens-Workforce-JSNA-Data-Profiles-2016-Supporting-the-Health4Families-Programme-1.xlsx&quot;&gt;West Sussex Children's Workforce Public Health data profile (2016)&lt;/a&gt; is now available to download.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
This profile is an interactive dashboard that summarises a wide range of data relating to the early years (e.g. demographic, socioeconomic, health and early years) and is published at Children and Family Centre (CFC) level. The profile aims to help the Children’s Workforce monitor changes in the health and wellbeing of the under 5 population within their centre area and supports the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sussexcommunity.nhs.uk/services/servicedetails.htm?directoryID=22580&quot;&gt;West Sussex Health4Families Programme&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
This provides an update on data published in the &lt;a href=&quot;http://jsna.westsussex.gov.uk/core-datasets/tools-resources/&quot;&gt;2015 profile&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Further information about the profile is included in the following slides:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;embed src=&quot;http://jsna.westsussex.gov.uk/wp-content/uploads/2017/01/Overview-for-website.pdf&quot; width=&quot;650&quot; height=&quot;525&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/embed&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>PHSRU</name></author><category term="health-profile" /><summary type="html">The West Sussex Children's Workforce Public Health Data Profile (2016) is now available to download</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The West Sussex Tobacco Control Needs Assessment has now been published</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/needs-assessment/west-sussex-tobacco-control-needs-assessment-now-published/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The West Sussex Tobacco Control Needs Assessment has now been published" /><published>2016-12-09T09:13:50+00:00</published><updated>2016-12-09T09:13:50+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/needs-assessment/west-sussex-tobacco-control-needs-assessment-now-published</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/needs-assessment/west-sussex-tobacco-control-needs-assessment-now-published/">&lt;p&gt;As a population we're living longer but spending more years in poor health and in need of health and social care services. Tobacco−free living helps people live healthier for longer by reducing a person's risk of developing tobacco related diseases. Tobacco remains the single major cause of preventable ill−health and death.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tobacco control is a scientifically proven program that seeks to address the preventable ill-health, death, disability and other consequences of tobacco use.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;color:#1499DB&quot;&gt;A comprehensive approach to tobacco control in West Sussex will:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol style=&quot;list-style-type:circle&quot;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Protect children from harm, giving them a better start in life&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Boost the disposable income of the poorest and help lift them out of poverty&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cuts costs to local public services such as the NHS, social care services, fire services etc&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Improve key measures of population health (e.g. deaths from cancer, heart disease, respiratory disease, number of children living in poverty, sickness absence)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The West Sussex Public Health and Social Research Unit have reviewed local and national evidence and engaged with the public and professionals to identify the current and future tobacco control needs across the county. Based on the evidence, the &lt;a href=&quot;http://jsna.westsussex.gov.uk/wp-content/uploads/2016/12/TCNA-FINAL-report.pdf&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Tobacco Control Needs Assessment&lt;/a&gt; (TCNA) will help inform the development of local priorities and guide commissioning of tobacco control activities. The appendices document containing findings from key stakeholder engagement activities is also available &lt;a href=&quot;http://jsna.westsussex.gov.uk/wp-content/uploads/2016/12/TCNA-appendices-final.pdf&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The infographic summary below showcases the main facts and key actions identified in the Needs Assessment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;embed src=&quot;http://jsna.westsussex.gov.uk/wp-content/uploads/2016/12/TCNA-Briefing-Infographic-WSx-final.pdf&quot; width=&quot;650&quot; height=&quot;525&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The three documents can also be found by clicking on the links below:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://jsna.westsussex.gov.uk/wp-content/uploads/2016/12/TCNA-FINAL-report.pdf&quot;&gt;TCNA FINAL report&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://jsna.westsussex.gov.uk/wp-content/uploads/2016/12/TCNA-appendices-final.pdf&quot;&gt;TCNA appendices final&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://jsna.westsussex.gov.uk/wp-content/uploads/2016/12/TCNA-Briefing-Infographic-WSx-final.pdf&quot;&gt;TCNA Briefing Infographic WSx final&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/embed&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>PHSRU</name></author><category term="needs-assessment" /><summary type="html">As a population we're living longer but spending more years in poor health and in need of health and social care services. Tobacco−free living helps people live healthier for longer by reducing a person's risk of developing tobacco related diseases. Tobacco remains the single major cause of preventable ill−health and death. Tobacco control is a scientifically proven program that seeks to address the preventable ill-health, death, disability and other consequences of tobacco use. A comprehensive approach to tobacco control in West Sussex will: Protect children from harm, giving them a better start in life Boost the disposable income of the poorest and help lift them out of poverty Cuts costs to local public services such as the NHS, social care services, fire services etc Improve key measures of population health (e.g. deaths from cancer, heart disease, respiratory disease, number of children living in poverty, sickness absence)   The West Sussex Public Health and Social Research Unit have reviewed local and national evidence and engaged with the public and professionals to identify the current and future tobacco control needs across the county. Based on the evidence, the Tobacco Control Needs Assessment (TCNA) will help inform the development of local priorities and guide commissioning of tobacco control activities. The appendices document containing findings from key stakeholder engagement activities is also available here. The infographic summary below showcases the main facts and key actions identified in the Needs Assessment. The three documents can also be found by clicking on the links below: TCNA FINAL report TCNA appendices final TCNA Briefing Infographic WSx final</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Release: National Child Measurement Programme (NCMP) 2015/16</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/data/release-national-child-measurement-programme-ncmp-201516/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Release: National Child Measurement Programme (NCMP) 2015/16" /><published>2016-11-08T09:12:52+00:00</published><updated>2016-11-08T09:12:52+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/data/release-national-child-measurement-programme-ncmp-201516</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/data/release-national-child-measurement-programme-ncmp-201516/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;NHS Digital have released the &lt;a href=&quot;http://content.digital.nhs.uk/searchcatalogue?productid=23381&amp;q=national+child+measurement+programme&amp;sort=Relevance&amp;size=10&amp;page=1#top&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;National Child Measurement Programme (NCMP)&lt;/a&gt; results for the 2015/16 school year. &lt;/b&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Children in reception class (aged 4 to 5 years) and year 6 (aged 10 to 11 years) have their height and weight measured to assess overweight and obesity levels in children within state-maintained primary schools. This data is used at a national level to support local public health initiatives and inform the local planning and delivery of services for children.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The West Sussex Public Health and Social Research Unit have completed a &lt;a href=&quot;http://jsna.westsussex.gov.uk/wp-content/uploads/2016/11/Final-Data-Briefing-1516-National-Child-Measurement-Programme.pdf&quot;&gt;data briefing (NCMP: 2015/16)&lt;/a&gt; to summarise childhood obesity prevalence at a local level.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;color:#1499DB&quot;&gt;Key Facts &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol style=&quot;list-style-type:circle&quot;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In England, &lt;b&gt;over a fifth&lt;/b&gt; of reception children were overweight or obese, and in year 6 it was over a &lt;b&gt;third&lt;/b&gt;. Nationally, the prevalence of obesity has &lt;b&gt;increased&lt;/b&gt; since 2014/15 in both reception and year 6&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In West Sussex, prevalence of obesity was &lt;b&gt;lower than national&lt;/b&gt;, but not regional levels; with 19.9% of reception age children (4-5 years old) and 30.4% of year 6 children (10-11 years old) measured as overweight or obese&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Within local authorities, the prevalence of overweight and obesity is varied. For both school years, there was no significant change in the percentage of overweight/obese children for any one local authority within West Sussex compared to the previous year.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;embed src=&quot;http://jsna.westsussex.gov.uk/wp-content/uploads/2016/11/Final-Data-Briefing-1516-National-Child-Measurement-Programme.pdf&quot; width=&quot;650&quot; height=&quot;525&quot; /&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>PHSRU</name></author><category term="data" /><summary type="html">NHS Digital have released the National Child Measurement Programme (NCMP) results for the 2015/16 school year. Children in reception class (aged 4 to 5 years) and year 6 (aged 10 to 11 years) have their height and weight measured to assess overweight and obesity levels in children within state-maintained primary schools. This data is used at a national level to support local public health initiatives and inform the local planning and delivery of services for children. The West Sussex Public Health and Social Research Unit have completed a data briefing (NCMP: 2015/16) to summarise childhood obesity prevalence at a local level. Key Facts In England, over a fifth of reception children were overweight or obese, and in year 6 it was over a third. Nationally, the prevalence of obesity has increased since 2014/15 in both reception and year 6 In West Sussex, prevalence of obesity was lower than national, but not regional levels; with 19.9% of reception age children (4-5 years old) and 30.4% of year 6 children (10-11 years old) measured as overweight or obese Within local authorities, the prevalence of overweight and obesity is varied. For both school years, there was no significant change in the percentage of overweight/obese children for any one local authority within West Sussex compared to the previous year.</summary></entry></feed>